Guide to the Randolph Crump Miller Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Randolph Crump Miller Papers
1932-1997
RG 173
Yale University Divinity School Library
13
27 boxes
Writings,notes, and collected material document Miller's work. Randolph Crump Miller was a professor of Christian Education at the Yale Divinity School.
Miller, Randolph Crump, 1910-2002
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of R. C. Miller
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers
Biographical / Historical
Randolph Crump Miller was born in Fresno, CA on October 1, 1910, the son of the Reverend Ray Oakley Miller and Laura Belle Crump Miller. He earned his B.A. degree from Pomona College in 1931. Miller came to Yale to study with Luther Weigle, Hugh Hartshorne, Robert Calhoun, and Douglas Clyde Macintosh. He was a special studnet at Episcopal Theological School in Cambridge, MA during 1935-1936 and received his Ph.D. from Yale in 1936. Miller was ordained in the Protestant Episcopal Church in 1935.
From 1936 to 1952 Miller taught at Church Divinity School of the Pacific, Berkeley, CA. He was also chaplain to Episcopal students at the University of California through 1940. In 1952 Miller returned to Yale as Professor of Christian Education on the Luther Weigle Fund. Upon the retirement of Paul Vieth in 1964, Miller became the Horace Bushnell Professor of Christian Nurture at Yale Divinity School. Miller received a D.D. from the Pacific School of Religion in 1952 and a D. D. from Episcopal Theological School in 1961. He became Professor Emeritus at Yale in 1981.
Over the course of his career, Miller wrote eighteen books (several translated into Japanese and Korean) and published many articles. His books include What We Can Believe, Biblical Theology and Christian Education, Christian Nurture and the Church, Your Child's Religion: A Practical Guide for Parents, The American Spirit in Theology, This We Can Believe, and several others. His 1950 book, The Clue to Christian Education, was highly influential in the field of religious instruction. Miller gave sermons, lectures, and workshops throughout the United States and abroad. A jazz enthusiast and expert, Miller spoke widely on the theology of jazz, as well as on topics in theology and Christian education. From 1958-1978 he was editor of the interfaith journal, Religious Education, published by the Religious Education Association.
Professor Miller was a member of the Episcopal Evangelical Fellowship and the Religious Education Association. He was a trustee of the periodicals The Churchman and the Anglican Theological Review, and served as a consultant in Christian education for the National Council of Protestant Episcopal Churches. He served as director of Christian education at Trinity Church on the Green in New Haven from 1961-1971.
For more biographical information, see Miller's Festschrift: Process and Relationship, edited by Iris Cully and Kendig Brubaker Cully (Birmingham, AL: Religious Education Press, 1978).
Scope and Contents
Randolph C. Miller exerted a profound influence on religious education in the U.S. and throughout the world as professor of Christian education and theologian of process and relationship. These papers complement other the significant holdings in the field of religious education at the Yale Divinity Library, including the papers of George Albert Coe and Paul Vieth, and the archives of the Religious Education Association and the Association of Professors and Researchers in Religious Education.
Series I, Published Articles and Pamphlets, includes writings that Miller published throughout his long career. Many of these articles were gathered by the library over a period of years. Other articles by and about Miller are interspersed in the Alphabetical Files of Series III, which represent Miller's own office filing system. Series II, Manuscripts and Drafts, contains primarily typescript versions of articles and booklength writings that later appeared in published form. There are also typescript sermons in this series. The Alphabetical Files of Series III provide an excellent snapshot of Miller's accomplishments and interests. The Scrapbooks of Series IV contain material similar to that found in Series I and III, just in a different format. The Notes of Series V are Miller's handwritten notes for sermons, talks, etc. on a wide variety of topics. Series VI, Audio-Visual Material, includes a five-part video series entitled "A life in Education; A Conversation with Randolph Crump Miller" and a two-part audio series entitled "Theology of Jazz."
Arrangement
I. Published Articles and Pamphlets
II. Manuscripts and Drafts
III. Alphabetical Files
IV. Scrapbooks
V. Notes
VI. Audio-Visual Material
VII. Biographical Material
Religious education; Educators; Miller, Randolph Crump, 1910-2002; Yale University -- Faculty
- Published Articles and Pamphlets, Series I
  - Bibliography of published works by RCM, no date (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - The Abundant Life, a son's memorial to his father, The Churchman, pp. 10-11., 1958 December (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Anxiety and Christian Education, The Pulpit, v. 28, no.4, pp. 4-5,18., 1957 April (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Books Children Own, The Churchman, pp. 10-11., 1953 April (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - "Bobby-Sox" Religion, Religious Education, pp. 107-113., 1946 March-April (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Challenge of the Church: A Course on the Work of the Church for High School Students, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 284)
  - The Challenge of the Ecumenical Movement to Church Education, Religious Education, pp. 369-376., 1966 September-October (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Christian Education as a Theological Discipline and Method, Religious Education, pp. 1-6., 1953 November-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Christian Insights for Marriage, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 294)
  - Dewey, Whitehead, and Christian Education, Lexington Theological Quarterly, pp. 111-121., 1985 October (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - The Easter Event and Linguistic Analysis,Near East School of Theology Quarterly, pp.6-21, 1967 April, July (Box 24, Folder 284)
  - Educational Mission of the Church, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 295)
  - Empirical Method and its Critics, Anglican Theological Review, pp. 27-34., 1945 January (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Family Service, The Living Church, pp. 22-23., 1955 August (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - The Family Worships Together, Presbyterian Survey, pp. 16-17., 1955 August (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - The Family Worships Together, Baptist Leader, pp. 5-6, 16., 1957 September (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - From Where I Sit: Some Issues in Christian Education, Religious Education, pp. 99-105., 1965 March-April (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - From Where I Sit, Learning for Living, pp. 7-9, 1968 May (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - God as Idea and as Living. Christendom: Winter, 1946, pp. 57-64. (Part II in Learning for Living, 1968 Sep.), 1946, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Holy Spirit and Christian Education, The 1962 Rufus Jones Lecture. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Holy Spirit and Christian Education, Biblical Theology, pp. 49-59., 1962 October (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Is Temple a Realist? Journal of Religion: pp. 44-54., 1939 January (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Let's Explore the Philippines, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 296)
  - Martin Lectures at Perkins School of Theology: Horace Bushnell, Prophet to America's Children; God's Gift to the Imagination; A state Renewed in Righteousness, Perkins Journal, 1979 Spring (Box 24, Folder 285)
  - La missione educativa della Chiesa, La Scuola Domenicale, pp. 1-34., 1961 March-April (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Moral Behavior for Christians. Anglican Theological Review: pp. 3-11., 1965 April (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - My Life is This, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 297)
  - New Curriculum in Orthodox Churches, Overseas Mission Review, vol. XII, pp. 32-34, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 286)
  - The New Naturalism and Christianity. Anglican Theological Review: pp. 25-35., 1939 October (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Old Man and Liturgicum, The Witness, pp. 15-17., 1949 September 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Our Common Biblical Heritage, The Witness, pp.12-14, 1948 November 25 (Box 24, Folder 286)
  - Our Money's Worth in Christian Education, The Southern Churchman, 1949 September 10 (Box 24, Folder 287)
  - Pastoral Psychology and Christian Education, Pastoral Psychology, 8 pp., 1951 October (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Prayer Book and the Red Network, The Churchman, p. 12, 1945 November 15 (Box 24, Folder 287)
  - Probleme der Christlichen Unterweisung in den Vereinigten Staaten. Lutherische Rundschau: pp. 138-151., 1958 October (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Prophetic Religion and Culture, Religion and Education, pp. 33-39, Vol. 24 No. 1, 1997 (Box 24, Folder 288)
  - Protestant Nurture in a Changing World. Religious Education: pp. 201-206., 1961 May-June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Relevance of Christian Ethics. Religion in Life: pp. 205-215., 1945 Spring (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Religious Education Scene, The New Review of Books and Religion, v. iv, pp. 4, 24., 1980 June (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - (compiler) Some Asian Reflections on Christian Education. Religious Education: pp. 119-128., 1971 March-April (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Some Weaknesses and Resources of the Christian Church, The Journal of Religious Thought, pp. 16-33., 1946-1947 Autumn-Winter (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Something New in Religious Education, The Churchman, pp. 6, 12., 1955 May (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Theology and the Understanding of Children, Pastoral Psychology, 7 pp., 1952 June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Theology in Transition. Journal of Religion: pp. 160-168., 1940 April (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - What Kind of Church is the Episcopal Church? It it Protestant or Catholic? Decently and In Order, The Pacific Churchman, 3 pp., 1941 June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Whitehead and Religious Education. Religious Education:pp. 315-322., 1973 May-June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Book reviews by RCM, 1956, 1960, no date (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Reviews of works by RCM, 1956, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 14)
- Manuscripts and Drafts, Series II
  - American Theology Today, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - The Art of Dying (published as Live Until You Die, 1973) (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Be Not Anxious -- 3 drafts (published in 1957) (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Be Not Anxious - continued (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Biblical Theology and Christian Education (published in 1956) (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Broken Bones, no date (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Christianity in the World Today (sermon) (Box 24, Folder 289)
  - A Congressional Investigation of the Prophets, no date (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Consultation on the Teaching of Practical Theology, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - The Clue to Christian Education (Box 24, Folder 289)
  - Dewey, Whitehead and Christian Education, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - The Doctrine of Grace: Its Biblical Interpretation (Box 24, Folder 290)
  - Douglas Clyde Macintosh: A Centennial Tribute (contributor) (1978) (Box 24, Folder 290)
  - Education for Living, no date (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - An Empirical Quest for God, circa 1947 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Final Examination Questions, no date (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - God and the Nation (Box 24, Folder 290)
  - Horace Bushnell: Prophet to America's Children, no date (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - I Remember Jesus (published in 1958) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Images of Man and the American Scene (published in What is the Nature of Man? Images of Man in our American Culture, 1959) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Influence of William James on Religion, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Kyrkans Uppfostrande Mission (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Drafts for The Language Gap and God; Religious Language and Christian Education, 1970.: "The Language Gap and God" (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Drafts for The Language Gap and God; Religious Language and Christian Education, 1970.: "Linguistic Analysis and Religious Education" (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Drafts for The Language Gap and God; Religious Language and Christian Education, 1970.: "Religious Language and Christian Education" (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Lectures on the Nature of the Church and Christian Education, 1954 (basis for Christian Nurture and the Church, 1961) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Living With Anxiety (published in 1971) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Models of MInistry (sermon, 1987) (Box 24, Folder 291)
  - A More Effective Church (sermon) (Box 24, Folder 291)
  - The Mystery of God, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Notes from a Chaplain's Diary, no date (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - The Old Man and the Prayer Book (Box 24, Folder 291)
  - Our Faith and How We Communicate It (Address, 1956) (Box 24, Folder 292)
  - Professor Macintosh and Empirical Theology (Box 24, Folder 292)
  - Religion is any Subject, no date (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Rethinking Empiricism in Theology, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - The Spirit of American Theology (published as The American Spirit in Theology, 1974) (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
  - The Spirit of American Theology (published as The American Spirit in Theology, 1974) (continued) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Stories on the Drama of Redemption for 10th Grade, no date (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - A Symphony of the Christian Year (published in 1954) (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - The Theory of Christian Education Practice: How Theology Affects Christian Education (published in 1980) (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
  - The Theory of Christian Education Practice.. (cont'd) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Things are happening at C.D.S.P., no date (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Your Child's Religion -- 2 drafts (published in 1962) (Box 5, Folder 27-30)
  - What We Believe and What We Do [also "This We Can Believe"] (published as "What We Can Believe", 1976) (Box 6, Folder 31-33)
  - What is Love? (Box 24, Folder 292)
  - Whither? A Treatment of the Future of Religion, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 12)
- Alphabetical Files, Series III
  - Adam, Eve and Darwin (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Adnee Hall Lectures on Youth on the "Church's Ministry to Youth", 1958 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Adult Christian Education in the Church, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Alexander, Hartley Burr, a Special Report on the Epistemology of Anxiety and Christian Education., 1957 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Anxiety and Learning, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - A Barber's Dream, Forth, 1948 Mar (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Article about Miller: The Southern Churchman, 1949 Oct (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Article about Miller: Randolph Crump Miller: Theologian-Educator, by Sara Little; Religious Education, Special Edition: Pioneers of Religious Education in the 20th Century: A Festschrift for Herman E. Wornom., 1978 Sep-Oct (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Authority and Freedom in Doctrine, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Beecher Lectures, Yale University, 1933 or 1934 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Bergson, Henri: writings re. (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - In Estimation of Bergson (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Beware of Spiritual Sabotage: A Needed Warning to Careless Americans, The Churchman, 1942 Mar 15 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Bible, writings re., 1934-1936. (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - The Bible as Literature, Lectures on, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Biblical Theological Workshop, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Bibliographies by Miller (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Bibliographies of Miller's writings (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Book Notes (by Miller), published in Findings, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Book reviews by Miller (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Book reviews of Miller's works (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Book reviews of: The Clue to Christian Education, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - The Theory of Christian Education Practice (Box 8, Folder 54-55)
  - Bushnell: Martin Lectures (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Bushnell, the Family and Children, Religious Education, 1979 May-Jun (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Catholic Education, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Children, writings re.: (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Children's Questions About Faith (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Half of His Religion at Three (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Christian Education, writings re. (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Christian Education as a Theological Discipline and Method. (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Christian Education in a Secular Society, Lutheran Education, 1966 Sep (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Christian Education in the United States, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Christian Education Report, The Southern Churchman, 1949 Sep 10 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Christian Faith and Life Series (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Church, writings re.: (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - The Middle is Always Up (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - You Need the Church (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - The Church and Christian Education: Eden Lectures, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - The Church and Christian Education: Notes (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - The Church and Christian Education: Chapter 1: A Class is Not a Group (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Church as a Redemptive Community: writings, speeches re. (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - The Church School of Tomorrow, The Southern Churchman, 1945 Sep 1 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - The Church's Nature and Christian Education. (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Climbers of the Steep Ascent, by Mary Jennes; Revised, introduction and several chapters by RCM, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Comparative Religions, writings and notes re., 1932-1936, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Concordat - A Working Principle (letter to the Editor), The Southern Churchman, 1940 Oct 19 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Confirmation, letter re., 1958 Feb 16 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Conscience and Compromise, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Contemporary Images of Man. (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Continuity and Contrast in the Future of Religious Education, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Creeds, writings re.: The Apostles' Creed and the Modern Man (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Creeds, writings re.: Where Our Creeds Came From (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Curriculum Development, writings re.:Lessons the Children Like (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Day by Day - Meditations for the week of July 17-23, 1960:We Love Because..., 1960 Jul (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Day by Day - Meditations for the week of July 17-23, 1960: Jesus Loves Me, 1960 Jul (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Day by Day - Meditations for the week of July 17-23, 1960: Don't Be a Diotrephes, 1960 Jul (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Day by Day - Meditations for the week of July 17-23, 1960: Loving God Means..., 1960 Jul (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Day by Day - Meditations for the week of July 17-23, 1960: The Body of Christ, 1960 Jul (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Day by Day - Meditations for the week of July 17-23, 1960: Be Not Anxious, 1960 Jul (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Day by Day - Meditations for the week of July 17-23, 1960: Nobody Loves Me, 1960 Jul (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Democracy in the Church (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Dewey, Whitehead and Christian Education, Lexington Theological Quarterly, 1985 Oct (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - "Dialog Sermons" for Radio, The Southern Churchman, 1949 Jul 30 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Do We Need an Ordained Ministry?, The Pulpit, 1967 May (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Education for Christian Living: Chapter manuscript, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Education for Christian Living: brochure, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Education for Christian Living (evaluations) (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Education for Living (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Education for Living in a Changing World: A Protestant Viewpoint (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Education for Redemption, International Journal of Religious Education, 1956 Mar (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Education in the Episcopal Church: Offsetting a Basic Sickness, The Churchman, 1946 May 15 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - The Education of Christians, The Pulpit, 1956 May (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Education to Be the Church - Outline of lectures by RCM at St. Augustine's College, Canterbury: Chapters 1-5 (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - Education to Be the Church - Outline of lectures by RCM at St. Augustine's College, Canterbury: Chapters 6-12 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Empiricism, writings re.: Empirical Method and Its Critics (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Empiricism, writings re.: Empiricism and Analogical Theology (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Empiricism, writings re.: Empiricism and Process Theology: God is What God Does (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Empiricism, writings re.: The Importance and Limitations of Empirical Method in Religious Knowledge (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Empiricism, writings re.: Meanings of Empiricism (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Empiricism, writings re.: The New Naturalism and Christianity (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - The Essence of Christianity (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Ethics, writings re. Americanism, Communism and Fascism (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Ethics, writings re. The Growth of the Hebrew Idea of God (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Ethics, writings re. The Relevance of Christian Ethics (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Ethics, writings re. A Review and Critique of Hartmann's Ethics, 1934 Jun (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Ethics, writings re. What Do We Mean By Moral Values, Ethical Decisions, Spiritual Resources? (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Ethics, writings re. Class notes: subjects include Greek Ethics, Christian Ethics, Prophets, Deuteronomic School, Book of Enoch, God in the Book of Job, Historical Approach to Yahweh, Religious Ideas of Israel, New Testament, Ethics of Paul, Canonical Subjects in Modern Ethical Problems, Moral Theology, Treatment of Sin. (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Evangelical Education, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Evangelism, Theology and Christian Education (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Experience and Revelation (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - Family, writings re.: The Big Family (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Family, writings re.: Six Paragraphs on the Christian Home (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Family, writings re.: What is Your Family Religion? (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Family, writings re.: When Parents Try to Act Like God (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Family, writings re.: (This folder also includes a student's paper entitled "Reflections on the Religious Possibilities of Youth Fellowship" by Patty Farr, 1975) (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Family Worship, writings re.: Esmeralda and Redemption (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Family Worship, writings re.: Family Church Service schedules (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Family Worship, writings re.: The Family Worships Together, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Family Worship, writings re.: Parents Go to Church School (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Family Worship, writings re.: Redemption in the Family (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Family Worship, writings re.: A Teacher's Summer Reading (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Family Worship in Religious Education, writings re.:Family Corporate Worship (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Family Worship in Religious Education, writings re.: Family Corporate Worship (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Family Worship in Religious Education, writings re.: The Family Service in the Seabury Series (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Family Worship in Religious Education, writings re.: Family Worship in the Church (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Family Worship in Religious Education, writings re.: Morning Prayer, The Witness, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Family Worship in Religious Education, writings re.:Worship and Education (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Festschrift for Randolph Crump Miller - Process and Relationship: Issues in Theology, Philosophy, and Education (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Festschrift for Randolph Crump Miller - Process and Relationship: Writings, Correspondence re., 1976-1978 (Box 11, Folder 114)
  - Focal Points for Christian Education (with Henry H. Shires), The Chronicle, 1947 May (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Food for the Spirit (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - For the World of Tomorrow, Christian Century, 1964 Apr 29 (Box 11, Folder 117)
  - General Convention of the Protestant Episcopal Church, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - God and Suffering, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - God and You: preface to Forward Movement daily meditations (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - God in a World at War: What Can Be Said of the Loving Father?, The Churchman, 1940 Feb 15 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - God is What God Does, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - The God of the Bible (Box 11, Folder 123)